WWW.MY-SUBS.COM
12 Champions...
Survivor is that ultimate test.
There's no room for failure.
..12 Contenders...
I'm willing to do what
needs to be done to win.
Champions, we're coming for you.
Go!
..playing the greatest game...
Give it all you've got.
That's why you're here!
Arrgh!
Come on, boys!
..Australian Survivor has ever seen.
Arrgh, arrgh...
One by one...
Nova, Steven, Shaun, David, John.
..they were voted out...
The tribe has spoken.
..until just three remain.
Baden...
Survivor has definitely
pushed me to my limits.
But now I want the title.
..Harry...
I've done a lot of sneaky things
and I didn't work hard to just
hand the win over to someone else.
..Pia.
I said that if I wasn't
the first one out,
I'd be the last one standing.
So I'm just going to give it my all
and I'm going to fight to the death.
One Champion, two Contenders.
Who will be crowned Sole Survivor?
I'm here at final three.
While it's been an amazing experience...
..I'm ready to finish this game
because I'm actually now
in the box seat to win.
I'm the ultimate Contender.
I've had four jobs, worked
for everything I have.
And since day one I've
played this game hard.
We're down to hours
until final challenge,
final tribal council,
$500,000.
I'm so close I can basically taste it.
This is the ice-cream
truck that I have wanted
since I was five years old.
This is marrying my girlfriend.
I might be up against a genius,
and an amazing Australian actress
but I feel like I played a
better game than both of them.
And I just need to
prove that to the jury.
I've had countless nicknames,
Dirty Harry, Harry
Houdini, the cockroach.
But right now, I'm just Harry Hills
and I'm going to be Sole Survivor.
Last night I took
away Luke's dream.
It felt really horrific to vote him out.
He's been a real ally of mine.
You know, I'm going to
sit with that decision
for the rest of my life.
Now I have to win it.
I owe it to him and I owe
it to myself to fight for this.
I want it to be for something. I
don't want it to be for nothing.
I'm the last woman standing and
I'm the last Champ standing.
I would love another
Champion to take it out.
And I would love to be that
champion. I'm their last shot.
I'm here because I
played the right game,
being incredibly social,
making smart moves on the sly.
And if I get to the final two,
I'm going to give a
kick-arse pitch to the jury.
And I'm hoping that I can win.
People do underestimate me.
I'm the shy, awkward PhD student.
Everyone I know back
home would be surprised
that I even applied to be on Survivor.
I don't think people expected
me to make it this far.
But here I am after 48 days
of challenges and tribals
and endless tests of my
physical and mental abilities,
I've only got one more challenge.
I've been so close to an individual
immunity win several times.
I really want to get that win
and not be carried to the
final two by someone else.
But also personally to
show everyone back home
that people like me can
do these sorts of things.
This is my last chance to win
that beautiful necklace.
We're going into war here.
I'm going to do everything
I can to beat Pia...
..taking Baden to the end, to final two.
That was always my plan.
And saying, "Hey. I'm a true Contender.
"And I deserve to win Sole Survivor."
Come on in, guys.
I'm so nervous
about today's challenge.
I know that if Harry
wins immunity today,
he's not going to take me to final two.
This will seal my fate in this game.
Arm strength.
I just have to do whatever
it takes to beat him.
He's gonna fight me to the death
and I'm going to do the same.
Guys, congratulations
on making it to Day 49.
You have outlasted 21 other
players to get this far.
That is no easy feat. Well done.
You ready to get to your
final immunity challenge?
- Yes.
- Of course.
First things first.
You're gonna have to take it off me.
You're not... you're not
going to help me, huh?
Nuh.
Alrighty.
For the last time, immunity
is back up for grabs.
If you only win one
challenge in this game,
this is the one to win.
For today's challenge
you're going to stand
on narrow pedestals
while holding onto ropes
attached to two heavy idols.
If at any point you drop an idol
or you take a foot off a pedestal,
you're out of the challenge.
Last person standing wins immunity
and a guaranteed spot in the final two
and a 50% chance of winning
a half million dollars
and the title of Sole Survivor.
Plus you will get to choose who's
gonna be sitting next to you
at that final tribal.
Everything is on the line today.
This is the one to win.
Now, because it's your final challenge
and you might need a
little extra motivation,
we have some people here
today to help cheer you on.
No...
Harry, who would you
most like to see today?
My family and Jordan.
Come on out, guys.
Hi, look at your beard.
Well done. I'm so proud of you.
I've missed you so much.
Nice to meet you.
Hi. I feel like I know you.
Harry, you want to introduce us?
This is my mum and this
is my girlfriend Jordan.
- Hi.
So, Harry, how does it feel
seeing Jordan after 49 days?
It's incredible.
Like...
..I feel like there's energy with me now
that I haven't had 49 days.
You're so skinny.
I've never seen his
beard this long before.
Your hair looks nice, though.
- So, Jordan, you know how much of
a superfan Harry is. - Yeah.
What do you think it means to him
to be standing here at
this final challenge?
Oh, God. This is absolutely
a dream come true for him.
I honestly knew that
he would get this far.
And to see him here, I'm
just... I'm so happy for him.
- I'm so proud of him.
- We're very proud of him.
He's done an amazing
job to get this far.
Obviously you guys have as well.
It's been a long time. We've
heard so much about you guys.
It's nice to finally see you as well.
It's like we know you,
especially you, Jordan.
Oh, that's good. I'm glad
you're talking about me.
So, Baden, are you ready
for a little love from home?
Oh, jeez. I don't know if I'll
ever be ready but I'm excited.
Let's find out.
Come on out, guys.
Cal!
Oh, you all came.
Good to see you.
It's so good to see you
guys. It's been so long.
- Look at you.
- What's going on?
I know. I know.
So, Baden, who do we have here?
So, we've got Mum and Dad
on my left, Glen and Karen,
and I've got my brother
Callum here as well.
I'm so glad they could
all make it and be here.
It's just... It's so special.
Just to have them come out
here and see me here.
Karen, did you think
he'd make it to Day 49?
Uh, no. Because at home his
nickname is the 'nutty professor'.
He's not very good at basic life skills.
So hopefully that's improved.
Maybe a little hopefully.
- Big change.
- Huge.
Glen, do you sense that he's changed?
Gosh, from the start I just
wouldn't have believed
he would have tackled a challenge
like this totally on his own.
Yeah. Very, very proud.
So, Baden, why did you want to play
this crazy game in the first place?
I applied just to show myself
that I can do things that I
didn't think were possible.
Like, I'm very risk averse back home.
I don't try things often.
And here I am after seven weeks.
I've had such a big experience here
and I've done so many things I
thought I would never be able to do
that I feel like a
different person almost
that I don't fully appreciate
until I get home again
how much I have changed.
Alright.
So, Pia, you stepped out
of a challenge 20 days ago
- to talk to your family on the phone.
- Yes.
- Are you ready to see them in the flesh?
Come on out, guys.
Oh, my God!
What happened to you? You're so big.
Hi.
Oh, my God.
Are you good?
How are you? You've gotten so big.
Look at your earrings.
Hi.
I'm so glad you came.
- I love you.
- I'm so glad you came.
So, Pia, introduce us to the tribe.
This is my husband Luke.
And this is my daughter
Lily and my son James
who's had a massive,
massive growth spurt.
- Are you a bit tired?
- No.
- Say hello. - Spin around, buddy.
Spin around that way. That's it.
Say hi. Are you gonna wave?
Hey.
So, Luke, what did you think
when Pia first came to you
and said, "Honey, I think I'm
going to go and play Survivor
"for a couple of months and you
can take care of the kids"?
I wasn't surprised because I know
how much she loves the show.
Did you think that she'd
make it this far?
Honestly I did. I kind of did.
It's alright. I didn't.
I thought voted out Day 1. Yeah.
I just... I just kind of...
I think she's incredible.
I know what she's capable.
I think it's in her nature to
maybe resist challenges like this
but once she puts her mind to
things she's... she's unstoppable.
And it just doesn't really
surprise me to see her here now
to be honest.
- Thanks.
- It's alright.
So, Pia, what does being away
from the family for so long
made you realise?
Mwah.
You know, I couldn't love them any more,
but I appreciate them on
such a deep level now.
Like, no part of my life
will I take for granted.
You know, silly things
like making lunches
or, you know, having to get
kids ready for school.
Sometimes you don't think
about how lucky you are.
And I think every single moment
that I get to spend with
these kids and Luke
is going to be even more special now
because I appreciate it
on such a high level.
What would it mean to you
to win this challenge today?
I've worked so hard and I've had so
many ups and downs to get here.
I mean, there's been times when
I thought I wasn't going
to make it even five days.
So just to win this challenge
would be incredible.
And to know that I have a
chance to get to the final two
and plead my case would be amazing.
Alright. Well, loved ones,
you're going to be cheering
on from the bench today.
I'm going to give everyone
a minute to catch up.
And then Pia, Baden, Harry
we're gonna get to it.
Oh, my goodness, it's
so good to see you.
- Look at my nails.
- I know.
They've been like this since Day 2.
Did you miss me?
- Mate. Thanks, mate.
- Good luck.
- This is gonna be fun, Harry.
- It's not going to be fun.
Did you say it's going to be fun?
A special kind of fun.
Oh, yeah. They feel nice, huh?
Nice and soft, you know, a bit cushy.
Alright, everyone.
Go ahead and grab your handles.
When you're ready, take up
your position on the pedestals.
Get a nice comfortable position
'cause you're gonna be here a while.
For immunity
and a spot in the final two...
..this challenge is now on.
Pretty simple challenge.
In each of those idols you
have 10% of your body weight.
You just need to keep both
feet on those pedestals,
both idols in the air.
But as is often the case in Survivor,
the simple ones can
be the most difficult.
Nothing comfortable about that position.
The pedestals are gonna start
grinding into the soles of your feet.
That discomfort soon is
going to turn into pain.
Then it becomes about pain management.
Mind over matter at that point.
Alright. That's it.
That's all I got to say.
I'll see you guys in four hours.
Hey.
Baden gonna try out Harry's position.
Baden almost knocks himself out.
Just finding somewhere
comfortable, Jonathan.
You really do not want to
slip in this challenge.
Ooh, a little slip from Baden.
Nothing to see here, right?
That's one hour, guys.
What's the record
for the longest challenge?
Six hours and 28 minutes is the record.
- Would they really last that long?
- They've just gotta push through it.
Baden is the only one up there
with a smile right now.
I would have loved to have
done some proper stargazing
while we're standing here, but...
If I look up, I think I might pass out.
I can see, like, three stars.
Yeah. I was looking up before.
You should see it from our
beach, Mum, it's beautiful.
The whole Milky Way,
all the different stars.
Yeah. Wow.
- So many shooting stars.
- Yeah. Excellent.
You know that you can use shooting
stars to determine winds, Jonathan.
- Really.
- Yeah.
Because the trail they leave
drifts with the wind.
Oh, interesting.
He's not actually
normally this talkative.
- Oh, really?
- Yeah. It's a changed person.
He chats a lot, don't you, Bay?
Did I tell you that everyone
calls me 'Bay' here?
- Bay?
- Bay.
- Like 'bay'. Like Chopper Bay?
- Yeah. Like, Bay.
Where else would you rather be?
Honestly, in the middle of Fiji
standing on some torture pegs.
Do you know how much
difference there is, though,
between, like, a dry crunchy
rice and like a risottoey rice?
Oh, my gosh.
Oh, Dad, how did Brighton do?
Did they get relegated?
Or are they safe?
Oh, the stars are back. Thank goodness.
We haven't been in a room
with walls in 49 days, Pia.
Why did we choose to do this?
Ooh. All good, Harry?
Yeah. I'm readjusting.
Is Harrison actually
you're full first name?
Arrgh! Oh...
Ow...
Pia in a serious amount of pain.
- Oh...
- Whoa.
- Harry.
Almost overbalances.
Nice save.
I love you.
Everyone giving it everything.
A lot of pain on Harry's face now.
Ow...
Guys, you've been up
there for five hours.
- Massive effort from everyone
- Good job, everybody.
Well done.
Arrgh! No...
Pia buckled over in pain.
Pia up on her toes, legs
shaking uncontrollably.
Just wondering how much
more of this she can take.
There's nothing but
pure agony on her face.
Hard to watch.
Oh, yeah. It's just hard.
Arms shaking.
Trying to find that inner
strength to keep going.
Hang in there, P, you can do it.
Just hang in there, sweetheart.
Just breathe. Breathe deep.
Just breathe.
Pia in an excruciating
amount of pain now.
Hey, P, sweetie.
I'm not gonna get any
more proud of you, OK?
Alright. so whatever you need
to do, you just do it, OK?
But I love you and I'm
so proud of you, OK?
So you just do your best.
I don't want to go home.
Just hang in there, kiddo. Kiddo.
If you don't want to go home,
just dig deep and hang in there, OK?
Think about the kids and
just work through it.
Just breathe. Just breathe.
Great job. Great job, sweetheart.
Pia really digging deep.
Giving it everything.
Guys, I just want to let you know
you've been up there for
six hours and 30 minutes.
Well done, guys.
You guys officially hold the
record for the longest challenge
in Australian Survivor history.
Wow!
Great job, everybody.
Keep going, Harry.
Now it's about who wants
that necklace the most.
Harry cannot control
the shake in his leg.
Arrgh!
Pia contorted in pain.
- JLP...
- Yeah.
Can you help me get down, please?
And after six hours and 40 minutes,
Harry steps out of the challenge.
Great effort. Take a seat.
Great job, Harry.
It was a great effort.
- Come here.
- Unbelievable effort.
We're left with two, Baden and Pia.
I can't move.
I think I have to get
down. I'm so sorry.
It's OK. Just do whatever
you have to do, sweetheart.
I'm so proud.
I'm trying to get down but I can't.
You want to get down? OK.
After over six hours and 40 minutes...
..that's it, Baden.
Thank you.
Baden, congratulations.
After six hours and 40 minutes...
Wow.
..you have won the final
individual immunity.
Oh, my God.
- Baden, come on over.
- Jonathan.
Turn around. Congratulations.
First individual immunity win,
guaranteed a spot at
that final tribal council
where you will have a chance
to plead your case to the jury.
It's just so special but mostly that
my family were here to see this.
I've come so close so many times
and it just means so much to me
that you guys are here for this one.
One big decision left.
Who are you gonna take
to that final tribal?
And who's gonna join the
jury at the end of tonight?
It's a lot to think about.
It's... That's huge.
- Guys, say goodbye to your loved ones.
- Yep.
And I'll see you guys tonight at tribal.
- See you, Mum. You can hardly walk.
- I know.
I got the victory I've
been craving for so long
and I could not be happier.
Nice to meet you guys. Nice to meet you.
And that's making me skip along
even though my feet are killing me.
But now it's actually kind of terrifying
how much power I hold at the moment.
I have no idea who to
take to the end with me.
And if I make the wrong choice here,
I could be dooming
myself to second place.
This is a half-a-million-dollar choice.
I'll now bring in the
members of our jury.
- Wow.
- Shaun.
- David.
- Wow. Baden's got it.
- John, Daisy...
- My God.
..Simon.
- Janine...
- Oh, my God.
Abbey,
and Luke, voted out
at the last tribal council.
Well, first of all, congratulations,
guys, for breaking the record
for the longest challenge in
Australian Survivor history.
Well done.
But after six hours and 40 minutes
Baden, it was you who walked out
of there wearing that necklace.
Now you have the power to decide
who's going to be in the final two.
Is that weighing on you?
Absolutely it's weighing on me.
It's the sort of power that you can
only dream of having in this game.
And there's definitely two major
things in my mind tonight.
The strength of both
Harry and Pia's games
and what the jury is looking
for in a player at the end.
Alright. Pia.
After the game that you've played so far
and your effort in the challenge today
do you think you deserve to be in
the final two more than Harry does?
I mean, I don't want to say I
deserve to be in the final two
more than Harry does.
But I definitely think
that Baden has a better
shot at winning against me.
These guys have played the game together
and they've made the same moves.
But Harry is a little more strategic.
If you put them both in the final two,
it will be harder for Baden
to own some of those moves.
Harry, what would you say to that?
I think the problem that
just got highlighted there
is that my game is already out there
but I've seen Pia's game
since the tribe swap.
And it's subtle, yes.
But if you think that it's
been a weak game in any way,
then you're dead wrong.
Walking into tomorrow's
tribal if Pia is here,
she's gonna have a lot of surprises.
On top of that,
there's a lot to be gained by
taking a fellow Contender here.
I mean, you just look at the numbers.
There's five Champions
and less than that in
Contenders at the moment.
If you're taking Pia,
you're against the odds.
I will say, though, with the Champions,
there are a few I voted out who,
I mean, actually all of
them except for Janine,
who are not happy with me.
I also didn't spend that much
time with the Contenders
so I'm not sure that there's
a lot of love coming my way.
And you did a really good
job working with Abbey
and that alliance of four.
You bamboozled me a lot
when I was going between,
like, Abbey and everyone
trying to save myself.
I really think there's a better chance
that if you took me you would win.
She sounds very convincing
right now to me.
I'm just saying.
I mean, she is a professional actress
and she's gone through this
game being quite deceptive
about how strong she is.
That's dangerous.
On that note, Baden, you
really have no idea
what these two are planning
to pitch to the jury.
Does that worry you?
It does worry me.
While I'm listening to
what everyone is saying
I can't take everything as being
completely truthful from them
because it benefits their game to
try and convince me to take them.
I mean, I've only known Pia since merge
and I had a bit of a holiday
from Harry in the middle
so I don't know their entire games.
But, um... But...
What was the question again?
Can I just clarify something
and be honest very quickly?
Absolutely.
I told Baden straight out that I
would like to take him to final two.
And that he didn't have to
promise anything to me.
And I said that purely because
I think Pia beats both of us.
Really.
No.
I think if you won today,
you wouldn't have taken me
because you would have taken Baden
because you think you can beat him.
You know that there's a lot of moves
that you feel like you can claim.
We've made some of the same moves
but Baden has made
probably better connections
with a whole lot of
people compared to me.
Baden spent more time with Luke.
Spent more time with Dave.
Spent more time with some
of the old Contenders as well.
But I do think that everyone's
been trying to get you out
and no one's been able to.
I would say that would
be your last big move
to take out the person that everyone
else has tried to take out.
You're willing to bet half
a million dollars on that?
That is the question tonight, isn't it?
OK. So, Harry, Pia, you
can't vote for Baden,
which means you can only
vote for each other
effectively cancelling each other out.
So, Baden, it is your
vote that will decide
who will be leaving this game and
become the final number of our jury.
Baden,
it is time to vote.
I'll collect the vote.
OK. Once the vote is read
the decision is final.
The person voted out
will be asked to leave the
tribal council area immediately.
I'll read the vote.
22nd person voted out
of Australian Survivor,
final member of our jury...
..Harry.
You need to bring me your torch.
Sorry, Harry.
- Don't worry about it.
- It's been amazing, man.
Harry.
We'll see you soon, mate.
Thank you.
Oh! Do it.
Harry, the tribe has spoken.
They sure have.
Time for you to go.
It's been an absolute privilege
to play with all of you.
Like, just an honour.
- Can't wait to see you guys tomorrow.
- See you tomorrow.
- That's exactly right, Harry.
- Give it your best.
Dang.
Well, congratulations.
You are the final two.
You've gone as far as
you can in this game,
and now it's up to these guys, the jury.
So, I suggest go back to
camp, get some rest...
..and think about how you're
going to convince them
that you deserve the
title of Sole Survivor
and the half million that goes with it.
Grab your torches, head on out.
Goodnight.
- Oh, my God, Baden.
- Right.
- I can't believe we did it.
- Final day.
- Look at us.
That will do it. Day 50.
- Pia.
- Final two.
- Congratulations, mate.
50 days ago I'd never even built a fire,
but here I am,
one step away from
becoming Sole Survivor.
That's overwhelming to me.
I've been thinking about playing
this game for almost 20 years.
It's my time to take this out.
But also, how many people
get to be this close
to winning half a million dollars?
I mean, I'm not someone
who has a lot of money.
Ever since my first big
role, Looking For Alibrandi,
I've been lucky to work
a lot as an actor.
But I still have to have other
jobs to support myself.
I teach.
This is a small industry
and I do it for the love.
We're a normal Aussie family,
we saved so hard to save
for a deposit for a house.
If I won the money I'd
pay off my mortgage
and have a better life for my kids.
Tonight I'm going into the final tribal.
I get to plead my case to the jury.
If I nail it...
..I could be going home and
changing my kids' lives.
I see a box.
- What is this?
- Oh, my God, Baden!
Food!
Oh, my God, there's bread and eggs.
- Oh, my God.
- Mmm!
I haven't had bread in so
long. Let's go smash it!
Holy cow!
- Oh, my God.
- We're going to be so full.
- Oh, my God. Yummy.
- Yummy.
Imagine how happy Harry
would be if he was here.
Oh, he would be cooking up a feast, eh?
Dammit, should have... No,
I shouldn't have kept him.
Final two feast.
That's a Survivor fan's dream. Isn't it?
- Here's cheers, Pia.
- Cheers.
- Is it OK?
- Mm!
It means more than I can describe
to be able to say that I
made it to the final day
of Australian Survivor, that I
surpassed all these other people.
Who would have thought
us two oddballs...
I know.
Think of the people
that were here, Baden.
All the athletes, all the
strategic masterminds.
We took them.
I just have one more to go
before I can claim the
title of Sole Survivor.
Back in the real world I'm a PhD student
who is introverted, shy,
cautious, risk averse.
I always struggled socially growing up.
I was terrified that one
day I might not belong.
I came into this game
looking to have a shot
and empower people like me.
While Survivor has definitely
pushed me to my limits physically,
I've had to be pushed more than
I've ever pushed myself socially.
I feel like I've transformed.
I've made good connections with people
and used that to be
able to get to the end.
This experience makes
me feel like I belong.
I am the last Contender
left in this game.
The nerds never get a chance
at something like this.
I'm fighting to show that even
your nerdy, awkward person
can come out here, play a social
game and win half a million dollars.
I just need to convince the
jury I deserve the prize
and the title more than Pia.
It's a scary task.
- I can't play for second.
- Nuh.
And I feel like Harry's
game was just so good.
Yeah.
Building up a
resume of good moves,
I made alliances, I made blindsides.
Harry, I took him out because I
looked at his game and my game
and went, "This is the scalp I need."
I do worry that some of them
will see me as a "goat",
someone who has been carried
to the end by others
so that they can be
crushed in the final tribal.
I need to sell the fact that
I've always been playing,
I haven't just watched and waited,
I've actually fought
really hard to be here.
I don't like talking about
myself. I don't like bragging.
But I'm looking tonight to
show that this transformation
is not for nothing and
that to complete it,
the title would be the
ultimate icing on the cake.
- This is it, Pia, 50 days.
- Oh, my God.
Do you know how long
I've wanted to do this?
Goodbye, fire.
Pink and blue.
- One pink, one blue.
- Battle of the ages. Cheers.
Cheers, Pia.
Tonight, there's nine people in
the jury standing between me
and me winning Sole Survivor.
It's a tough pitch.
Baden's got a lot of
friends on that jury
and the only person I didn't
put on that jury was Janine.
That's eight people who I've voted out.
They could easily vote
for him instead of me
because they feel hard done by.
I don't know if it's going to be
a hostile jury or a friendly jury,
but I just have to remind people
that I've played harder
and I should win.
This is more important than
anything I've ever done.
This is the final fight
and I'm ready to give the
performance of my life.
We'll now bring in the
members of our jury.
Shaun, David,
John,
Daisy...
..Simon,
Janine,
Abbey,
Luke and Harry.
Harry!
Voted out at the last tribal council.
Pia, Baden, congratulations.
You guys have gone as far
as you can go in the game.
But tonight, the power
now shifts to the jury.
Nine people you've had a hand
either directly or indirectly
in voting out from this game
will now decide which of
you two deserves the title
of Sole Survivor and the half
million dollars that goes with it.
Now, in a moment you'll each
make an opening statement.
This is your chance to pitch to the jury
why you think you
deserve to win this game.
The jury will then address you.
They'll ask you questions
and you'll answer them,
and then they'll have a chance
to respond to your answers
in an open forum.
Once everyone's said their piece,
the jury will then go up to vote
to decide who will win this game.
You guys ready?
Yeah.
Ready as I'll ever be.
Baden, take it away.
OK, here we go.
Um...
I came into this game as
someone who thought that
applying for Survivor
was a terrifying thing.
I came in super-awkward, super-shy.
I couldn't be the challenge beast
that somehow I got called at some point.
I didn't want to be the orchestrator
of the big strategic moves.
I knew that my best bet
was to play from the middle.
Get into good relationships
with as many people as possible
and hold as much information as I could.
I knew what the plays were going
into every single tribal council.
Just after tribe swap
I could see the
Contenders' strong alliance
was not going to last forever.
I started to make inroads
with the Champions,
and that started with Luke.
Once you get to merge,
I had the inroads with Luke and Dave
so that I had access to some
information from the Champions,
enough to keep myself
off the chopping block
as the Contenders crumbled.
In my mind, in this game, once you
get into the leader position
you have a very short amount of time
before you're kicked out of it,
normally out of the game entirely.
So my goal was to get into
that position as late as possible
and sit there at the end
with the power.
And that's what I did
at the very final challenge.
I knew that Harry would have
taken me to the final two
and Pia would have taken me to
the final two, so why did I fight?
Why didn't I just step down and save
myself the pain and the torture?
I did it because I needed that scalp.
I needed that big resume filler
at the end
to finish off this game
and take control of the game
right when it mattered most.
I understand that you might see my
game as something as more passive...
..but the moves are there,
and the move to intentionally stay
in the middle from beginning to end
is my claim to fame.
And I will own it tonight.
Pia...
..what would you like to say
to the jury?
Hi.
I came into this game
knowing that I was going to play
a social game.
You know, I wasn't going
to be the strongest,
but I knew that what I wanted to do
was be underestimated but
always be fiercely strategic.
Unfortunately I was thrown into a
tribe of very accomplished athletes.
Everyone wanted me out of there
because I wasn't athletic enough.
I really had to play hard.
I worked on Nova
and she changed the vote to
Anastasia and it saved me.
And then I really quickly
had to make alliances,
so I made an alliance of four.
And then we got Abbey and Roscoe
to switch to an alliance of six
and we did dominate.
We went to a tribe swap
and Janine became the Godmother
and I became the Smiling Assassin.
I went to a merge and we did
organise a blindside against Dave.
When finally my alliance
did turn on me...
..I knew that when people
were coming for me
I wanted to have a buffer of
strong people around me,
so they'd come for them first.
That buffer worked
because you came for Simon first
and then Janine.
I put most of you on that jury
except for you, Janine.
I did go to 20 tribal councils,
my name only came up in four
and I was never under threat.
I was always that slippery
little sucker that was there
and you didn't know you needed
to get me until it was too late.
As lovers of Survivor, I hope
that you will vote for the person
who played the best strategic game,
and I think we all know 100%
that that was me.
To vote for me as Sole Survivor
could change my life,
my family's life.
It was a joy to play with you all
and I thank you.
Thanks.
Alright, jury, you've heard
their pitches.
Now it's your turn to ask questions.
Shaun, would you like to kick it off?
- Guys.
- Hi.
- Hey, Shaun.
- Congratulations.
It's an amazing effort to go
50 days, you know, for anyone,
let alone, I guess, an actress
and a PhD student
who barely leaves his room.
But with no bullshit, no digressing,
I want to hear why you think the
other person doesn't deserve to win.
And I think I'd like to start with Pia.
Well, firstly, if you're looking
to vote for the person
who had the best personal growth
and who learned how to make friends
and had a good time out here, then you
absolutely should vote for Baden.
But you cannot vote for Baden
if you're voting for
the best strategic player.
I don't think Baden played
a strategic game at all.
I think he just sat next
to people who were really clever
and they kept him around
because he was an easy person
who would do what they said.
I would counter that
by saying that in my mind
your game has been you've worked
yourself into an alliance early on
and you rode that alliance
until it faltered.
You've been blindsided twice in a row
and then you've been taken through
to the final...
I wasn't blindsided twice. I knew
Janine was getting voted out.
You only say that afterwards.
Like, where's the evidence that...
No, I said it then.
I said it then, that night.
You said it that night,
that you knew that Janine was going?
She actually said to me,
she turned to me and went,
"Mate, we're screwed,
and it's probably you."
Um...
..sitting here with a jury
that probably has
some of the biggest challenge threats
and biggest strategic players
in the history of Survivor...
..personally I both consider
you guys goats.
I would like to hear the truth
on how you think your goat game
was advantageous to you,
and how did that get you to the end?
A goat is someone who follows.
I definitely didn't follow people.
If you are calling me goat, like,
does me blindsiding you not count?
The girls will back me up.
Janine, Abbey and myself were
the ones who thought of it
back at Contenders' camp where
Dave was gunning for Daisy.
I told the girls, and I said,
let's not wait to get you
before you got us.
I worked on Johnno and Harry.
So I had a really big hand
in voting Dave out,
but I had to be careful
because what happens when you
are at the forefront of moves?
You get voted out.
Dave,
you need to know where to sit
and how to make big moves
without being at the forefront
because this is Australian Survivor
and it's very different
to American Survivor.
And in Australia, if we see
someone taking control,
you're going to end up
sitting on the jury.
That's why you're there.
Dave, what I did not do is sit
at the back of an alliance,
at the bottom and
not make any decisions.
I'm not a goat.
I'm a hard-playing Survivor
and I deserve to be here.
And you think that I just sat and watched
every decision be made and didn't...
- I don't know your game well enough.
- OK.
I've put my piece many times in
groups of how I want the vote to go.
Sure.
Um... I'm not a goat.
I made moves. I...
I looked at the people coming
into the endgame and I thought,
"Who here do I have the best chance
of beating at the end?"
You look at Abbey, she's
a challenge threat,
she's played some great moves, she's
moved from alliances to alliances
at the right time to
keep herself above water.
Look at Luke, all the immunity
wins, idols and advantages
all the strategy.
And Look at Harry, he's also
played two idols perfectly
and played an incredibly wily game.
So I pegged my mark and
I said that... to myself
that if I had the choice I
would want Pia at the end.
But Baden, you didn't choose
to take me to the end,
you chose to vote me out and not Abbey.
So, clearly you wanted to take
Abbey to the end instead of me.
Wait, when did I choose to vote you out?
When Luke sent you away
from tribal council
you were going to vote
my name, not Abbey,
so clearly you didn't choose to take
me to the end from the beginning.
So that's not true.
I looked at the people
coming into the end game
and I thought, "Who here do I have the
best chance of beating at the end?"
So I pegged my mark and
I said that, to myself,
that if I had the choice I
would want Pia at the end.
But Baden, you didn't choose
to take me to the end,
you chose to vote me out not
Abbey, so that's not true.
Bay, I just would like
to ask you directly
do you think you played
a good social game?
Yes, absolutely, I played
a good social game.
I made sure that I had good
relationships with everyone.
I made sure that when it came
time to pick off Contenders
that I was seen as someone
that you didn't wanna get rid of.
I mean... My... I own my game.
I played from the middle.
Do you know how hard it is to manage
multiple alliances at the same time
and stop them from both turning on you?
There's a perception that I am
the person that you wanna take
because I won't be able
to put up a good fight
but I have... I'm
putting up a good fight.
I think that I can take Pia,
it's not a foregone conclusion here.
I've had to move from alliance
to alliance from group to group,
I didn't just ride one
alliance until it faltered.
And I've managed to do it in a way
where it's gotten me to the end.
I've gotta say, Pia...
..as a social player, I think
you're a social superwoman.
You are off the charts.
Thank you.
I was actually genuinely scared of you
because I thought, "My God,
please don't target me
"because you are seriously scary."
I see you as the wolf
in goat's clothing.
You were the reason why myself,
and I believe Abbey, got so far.
You were ruthless.
My question is can you please give
myself and this group some examples
of where the Smiling Assassin really
convinced people they're safe.
In the first half of the game,
almost every single
person who I voted out
thought I was their best friend
and they came up to me
just before the vote
and said, "Are you voting for me?"
And I said, "Oh, my God, no,
never." And I voted them out.
Like Susie, everyone, Nova...
I mean, Nova was a big one,
I sat there and had to
really make her happy
just before we blindsided her.
So I could have real
relationships with people
but I had no problem in separating
my relationships with people
and the game.
I really did work on making sure
people who were getting blindsided
didn't know they were
getting blindsided.
I'll vouch for you on that too
I think the conversation I had
before my blindside was, ah...
Yeah, made me feel a little too... too
comfortable, unfortunately.
Comfortable enough to
walk home with an idol.
Yeah. It was, pretty, you
know, pretty big for me.
Harry.
OK...
It's quite clear that...
..to use the analogy of, like,
drivers and passengers,
these two both, they're not
ever in the driver's seat
but they're the person beside
them sort of navigating.
The thing that I think is really
important from both of you
is that there is a fine
line between navigator...
..and passenger.
And you're really gonna
have to articulate that.
I have played a game where I
have controlled what people did.
I'm whispering in people's
ears, making suggestions,
steering them away from things.
Like, when we coming into merge,
I made sure that it was Dave who
was having the hate not Luke,
because I was working with Luke
and I pushed for that to be the case.
I was a part of many moves.
I never stepped into the driver's seat
but I didn't get
blindsided once by a result.
And I don't think that Pia can
say that, in complete truth.
- No, I definitely got blindsided.
- Yeah, exactly.
And then, at the end, you've not been
able to make the ultimate choice
about who to take with you.
Sure. But I didn't magically
appear here tonight.
- No, I'm not saying that.
- I'm here because I played hard,
because when my alliance
faltered, I knew it was coming
and I worked out how to save myself.
Having an alliance is not a weakness,
sticking with your alliance
is not a weakness.
Making big decisions at the
forefront of your alliance
is not a weakness.
I had to work out how to be strong,
how to be on the right side of votes,
how to manipulate votes without
people knowing I was doing it
and how to get people on the jury
without getting a target on my back.
I've worked with each and every
one of you on at least one vote
whether directly or indirectly.
My game was about
sitting in the position
where I had access to information.
I worked with alliances that
were working really well
and my alliances rallied
and we dominated.
But I think my game was something
that was enjoyable to be around.
I was someone who was
willing to vote anyone out.
I would do it with a smile on my face
if it meant that I would get further.
John.
We all came into the
game with a strategy,
be the beast, social
or strategy, whatever.
How did your social game make
you have to adapt throughout?
I've gone from being
this awkward shy person
to someone who's played a game
where people have not
wanted to get rid of me.
I've changed in this game.
I'm here, not just for me,
but people like me who feel that
they're a bit introverted or shy
and now I'm here, pleading
my case to you guys.
I've played an ultimate game
of sitting right in the middle.
I was seen as someone
who was more malleable,
more able to be worked
on than the others.
To get to the end, you need to know
when the time is right to strike
and when the time is right to hold.
And I made sure that I struck at
the time at the end of the game
so that there wasn't a
chance to be picked off.
Alright, Luke,
it's gonna be lucky last.
Do you have a question?
I'll just go to P...
ah, look, I like to think that I
helped save you twice in the game.
It's obviously got to,
like, where you are now.
I would've loved to have
that favour repaid.
It wasn't.
Why should I give you my vote?
Luke...
..voting you out was one of
the hardest things I had to do
because I know we've spoken about
how much we wanted to
win this for our families
and I will never get over...
..having to take that
dream away from you.
Last night, when I was standing on that
podium for 6 hours and 40 minutes,
I wasn't doing it so that
I could break a record,
I was doing it so that...
..if I took away your chance to be here,
I was gonna make damn sure
that I was here instead.
Because I didn't want voting
you out to be futile.
As much as I love working with
Harry I knew that if Harry won,
I was not gonna be sitting here
so I was ready to die up on that thing.
I think I played a great game.
I didn't have the best physical game
but in every single challenge, I
pushed myself to the absolute limits
to help my team, to be a good teammate.
Yes, I voted some of you out...
..but my game was a
really good social game,
it was a strategic game.
I certainly wasn't someone
who was sitting around,
waiting for people to
tell me what to do.
I was always at the forefront
of making decisions.
Just because I wasn't playing
a big game that was out there,
doesn't mean I wasn't
playing a big game.
I just wasn't stupid enough
to let everyone know
because I didn't wanna get voted out.
And that's why I'm sitting here.
Well said.
Mm.
Alright, guys, well, you
should have enough information
to decide who deserves the
title of Sole Survivor
and the half million that goes with it.
Remember, tonight, you
are voting for a winner.
For the last time, it is time to vote.
OK, guys,
you should have enough information now
to decide who deserves the
title of Sole Survivor
and the half million that goes with it.
Remember, tonight, you
are voting for a winner.
For the last time, it is time to vote.
Shaun, you're up.
Good.
I'll go count the votes.
Guys, it's been an incredible season,
the only thing left to
do, Pia and Baden...
..is to read the votes.
But, a moment like this should be
shared with people you love the most.
Oh!
Come on in, guys.
Oh, my God, it's Lily.
Hello!
Hello.
Say hi to my friends.
Say hi, Jamesy.
I can't believe that I'm here.
Can't believe this is happening.
Karen, how proud are you
of Baden right now?
- Extremely proud.
- Oh, Mum.
Especially after what
I watched last night.
What does it mean to see him
standing here on Day 50?
He's a changed person.
More confident, talking a lot more.
Even full of a bit of sass, last night.
Yeah.
I'm lost for words at the
moment, though. Jeez.
So Luke,
you think Pia deserves
to take this one out?
She...
I don't know, it's in the
hands of the jury, I guess.
Certainly... I'm just amazed
by everything she's achieved.
I can't get any prouder
of her at this point.
This is, to me, an affirmation
of everything that I've always
thought she's capable of.
Alright, guys, remember,
these votes are for a win.
I'm gonna read the votes.
First vote...
..Pia.
Pia. That's two votes Pia.
Pia. That's three votes Pia.
Pia. That's four votes Pia.
Winner of Australian Survivor, Pia.
Oh, Pia!
Wow! Oh, my God, Pia.
That was amazing.
Oh, my God!
Thank you, guys!
I gave it my best shot.
The dream.
She deserves it.
Your mum is incredible. Yeah?
Pia?
Here's your cheque.
Congratulations, you are
Australia's Sole Survivor 2019.
Go, Pia.
I can't believe I won Survivor!
I'm overwhelmed.
I just paid off my mortgage in
seven traumatising weeks.
Your mummy did such a great job.
My kids love Survivor
so to have them there
to see their mum win,
I'm so grateful that they
could share it with me.
This was the most amazing
experience in my life.
This is my friend Dave. Say hi.
I'm bonded with those people for life
and I've come away from
this a better person.
High five. Yee, boy!
Playing Survivor was a lifelong dream.
I always said that I was gonna
be first person voted out
or I would win and I
actually won!
Well, we went looking for Alibrandi
but I think we found Scarface.
You, for me, are the winner
of Sole Survivor in 2019.
Congratulations on that pitch.
I thought it was brilliant
so you've got my vote.
Your pitch has definitely
won it for me tonight.
I think you played a
great understated game.
Pia, wow, you played a
magnificent social game.
You surprised me big-time tonight.
I think you played a very subtle game,
um, I don't think you're a goat.
Congratulations, Pia.
I hope you enjoy the
title of Sole Survivor
'cause you've earnt it.
I have loved, loved, loved
playing this game with you.
You deserve it, you're
an amazing player.
You owe me dinner and a
night out with my family.
Alright.